<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ixai</title>
    <link>https://ixai.mx/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ixai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ixai.mx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder, or the dreaded nth post</title>
      <link>https://ixai.mx/post/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ixai.mx/post/placeholder/</guid>
      <description>As I iterate over the concept of a personal website for the nth, I&amp;rsquo;m once again reviewing what I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, dropping most (if not all) of it and rehashing &amp;ldquo;the first post&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;m not an avid blogger – most of my writing prowess is targetted at writing documentation – but I still like to do it every now and then. Although I hope it&amp;rsquo;s interesting for someone, I don&amp;rsquo;t think my site needs to be permanent, or that anything&amp;rsquo;s lost by rewriting it&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Docker images in GitLab CI</title>
      <link>https://ixai.mx/post/build-docker-images-in-gitlab-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ixai.mx/post/build-docker-images-in-gitlab-ci/</guid>
      <description>When implementing GitLab CI to build docker images, there were a few steps that weren&amp;rsquo;t immediately obvious from the documentation.
First, you need to add Docker as a service.
services: - docker:19.03.8-dind Second, you need to install the docker CLI. For debian-based systems, that&amp;rsquo;s docker.io, not docker.
before-script: - apt-get update - apt-get install docker.io -yqq Third, you need to point the docker CLI to talk to the Docker service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring and Dockerizing Shipit</title>
      <link>https://ixai.mx/post/exploring-and-dockerizing-shipit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ixai.mx/post/exploring-and-dockerizing-shipit/</guid>
      <description>I recently looked into Shipit to see if it was a fit for my team&amp;rsquo;s development workflow. The idea behind the merge queues seemed very attractive to me. Enter the setup guide:
 Deploying and hosting a Rails application is not trivial, and this document assumes you know how to do it.
In the future we&amp;rsquo;d like to provide it fully packaged inside a Docker container, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been done yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ixai.mx/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ixai.mx/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ixai Lanzagorta, a software engineer from México. I have a broad set of skills in web application development, operations, and systems administration.
I’ve been lucky to have lived and worked in highly multi-cultural environments, and spent extended time abroad in Japan, Vietnam, and the United States.
I value diversity, empathy and humility as much as I value ingenuity and technical proficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
